JACK MAHONEY

CHICAGO, IL

Phone Number: 517-574-8060 Email: mahone; 79@gmail.com LinkedIn: Jack's Profile GitHub: Jack's GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Jack is a technology professional with a background in cybersecurity, software engineering, and electrical engineering. Jack has experience in supporting infrastructure groups at various organizations, with various teams such as cloud, servers, network, storage and database, middleware, end-user compute, and application teams His technical expertise and familiarity with a wide range of technologies enable him to support end-user experience, risk analysis, and organizational maturity enhancements.

SKILLS

Software Engineering Skills:

- Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, React, Redux,
- Data: SQL, PostgreSQL
- Back-End: Node.JS, C
- Tooling: Visual Studio Code, Git, Azure DevOps, JIRA, ServiceNow, Amazon AWS, Azure Cloud

Additional Technical Skills:

- Expertise in cybersecurity principles, best practices, and industry standards such as NIST and ISO
- Familiarity with network technologies, protocols, and network segmentation strategies
- Understanding of server and end-user device security, including patch management
- Proficiency in disaster recovery planning, testing, and fault tolerance strategies

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Independent - Chicago IL

Present

- Primarily self-taught developer who has experience in developing with JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, React, HTML, and
 front-end components. Successfully built and deployed <u>jack-mahoney.com</u> website using modern front-end technologies and
 APIs to showcase proficiency in creating visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces
- Demonstrated expertise in version control using Git, ensuring efficient collaboration, code management, and seamless integration of new features and bug fixes for best practices in self managed environments. Experienced with debugging code and familiar with leveraging AI for increased efficiency

Cybersecurity Risk Management Lead, Infrastructure - Northern Trust - Chicago IL

August 2022 - Present

- Utilized familiarity with various programming languages and database technologies, to conduct comprehensive evaluations of the infrastructure team's technology components, as well as application development practices. Identified and prioritized potential risks and vulnerabilities, proposing effective mitigation strategies to protect critical assets and data. Initiatives led to effective responses of 100+ acknowledged information requests from regulators during horizontal exam
- Leveraged knowledge of cybersecurity principles and experience to work with application teams, providing directions for integration of robust security controls into both infrastructure and SDLC processes. The support of implementation and effective controls led to reduced infrastructure organizational risk ratings

Cybersecurity Senior Consultant - Optiv Security - Chicago, IL

July 2021 - August 2022

 Maximized cybersecurity maturity and IT asset value by helping clients understand business sectors for improvement based on NIST and ISO 27001 standards, licensing rules that create compliance risk, unnecessary spending, top cyber threats to the network (internal and external), securing the Software and Development Lifecycle (SDLC), and how the IT Asset Lifecycle fits into each organization's cybersecurity practice

Cyber Risk Consultant & Senior Consultant - Deloitte - Chicago, IL

January 2019 - July 2021

 Served multiple Fortune 500 clients, as well as other clients in a diverse array of industries, including the Financial Sector, Semiconductors & Electrical Components, Healthcare, Athletic Apparel, and the Education Sector on how to reduce overall cyber risk by leveraging industry leading practices for Asset Management at the foundational level

EDUCATION

Michigan State University | Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering